Guide to the Armistead T. M. Filler Papers, 1796-1945
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Armistead T. M. Filler papers 1796-1945
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Filler, Armistead T. M.
6.4 Linear Feet 4,821 Items
Lovettsville (Loudoun Co.), Va. resident. He was connected with the B. and O. Railroad Co., was a member of the Odd Fellows and the Democratic State Central Committee, and was treasurer of Loudoun Co.
Collection contains personal and official correspondence, business papers, and family records. Much of the business correspondence deals with the sale and purchase of guano and the financial affairs of "Linden," the Filler estate. Filler was a livestock speculator, had interests in the marble business, silver mines, and livestock insurance. Included are letters from Woodrow Wilson, J.K. Vardaman, Gen. Marcus Wright, McAdoo, and other prominent national figures. There is also a manuscript account of the cavalry battle of Traveler's Station.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Armistead T. M. Filler Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library in 1956.
Collection Overview
Collection contains personal and official correspondence, business papers, and family records. Much of the business correspondence deals with the sale and purchase of guano and the financial affairs of "Linden," the Filler estate. Filler was a livestock speculator, had interests in the marble business, silver mines, and livestock insurance. Included are letters from Woodrow Wilson, J.K. Vardaman, Gen. Marcus Wright, McAdoo, and other prominent national figures. There is also a manuscript account of the cavalry battle of Traveler's Station.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Filler, Armistead, T. M.
Filler family
Guano
Merchants -- Virginia
Merchants -- Correspondence
Business records -- Virginia -- Loudoun County
Loudoun County (Va.) -- History
United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Campaigns
Contents of Collection
- Correspondence Series, 1849-1945 and undated, (8 boxes)
  - 1849-1874 (Box 1)
  - 1875-1879 (Box 2)
  - 1880-1884 (Box 3)
  - 1885-1896 (Box 4)
  - 1897-1901 (Box 5)
  - 1902-1913 (Box 6)
  - 1914-1945 (Box 7)
  - undated (Box 8)
- Legal Papers Series, 1796-1926, (1 box)
  - 1796-1926 (Box 8)
- Printed Material Series, (3 boxes)
  - Calling cards (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous
  - Printed material (Box 9)
  - Invitations
  - Clippings (Box 9-10)
- Financial Papers Series, 1848-1943 and undated, (4 boxes)
  - Bills and Receipts
    - 1848-1870s (Box 10)
    - 1870s-1880s (Box 11)
    - 1880s-1919 (Box 12)
    - 1920-1943 and undated (Box 13)
- Bound Volumes Series, (2 boxes)
  - Bound Volumes (Box 14-15)
- Pictures Series, (1 box)
  - Pictures (Box 16)